

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Vision-driven change agent with career-long record of operations, business development, and management success for leading organizations

Proven talent for aligning business strategy and objectives with established business development and operations management paradigms to achieve maximum operational impacts with minimum resource expenditures. Growth-focused thought leader with wide expertise in business strategy, financial leadership, product development solutions, and trend analysis. Achieving optimal results with competent planning, organization, and solutions-oriented approach while driving business growth, profitability, and strategic alliances. Exceptionally dedicated professional with keen interpersonal, communication, and organizational skills.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Trends Research & Analysis
- Vendor Relations
- Account Management
- SEO
- Marketing
- Product Management

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

STARTSE UNIVERSITY, CALIFORNIA, JANUARY 2022 TO PRESENT

HEAD OF OPERATIONS | PRODUCT MANAGER

- Lead a team of 5 direct staff and manage a large-scale educational program.
- Create, organize, and implement workshops, presentations, and training events for 800+ participants.
- Liaise with, onboard, and build and nurture relationships with 100+ faculty, professionals, partners, and companies in Silicon Valley.
- Establish and implement short- and long-range goals, objectives, policies, and operating procedures.
- Monitors and evaluates operational effectiveness and effects changes required for improvement.
- Develop and execute systems/structures to enable effective day-to-day management, administration, and technical support.

GALLAUDET UNIVERSITY, WASHINGTON D.C., DECEMBER 2020 TO DECEMBER 2021

WEB DEVELOPER

Content Marketing

Event Management

Program Development

- Utilized WordPress development, various plugins and scripts, web applications, and language, including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, and PHP, building strong expertise and practical experience.
- Developed an extensive understanding of the UI, cross-browser compatibility, general web functions, and standards.
- Coordinated web functions, monitored web activities, incorporated new technologies, and enhanced existing websites.
- Worked collaboratively with faculty, staff, and administration on website development.
- Created new web pages and templates and updated existing web pages as necessary; re-designed and realigned graphical elements and page layouts as requested and utilizes current technologies to ensure proper display of the website on various devices.
- Recommended and implemented processes, methods, and programs to continually improve systems.

SELF-EMPLOYED, REMOTE., JANUARY 2015 TO DECEMBER 2020

FREELANCER

- Developed strategic foresight and reports for clients.
- Worked on marketing strategies (plans for the success of the project) for entrepreneurs, freelancers launching new projects, and small businesses such as ecommerce and travel agencies.

KRYSTEL LEAL Page 2

- Wrote hundreds of articles and other pieces with a focus on SEO and generating organic traffic.
- Specialized in front-end development using WordPress and created dozens of websites, personal blogs and e-commerce projects.

EDUCATION AND CREDENTIALS

SPECIALIZATION IN FUTURES THINKING, 2020

Institute for the Future, Palo Alto, California

BACHELOR OF STUDY (B.Sc.) IN COMMUNICATION AND MEDIA STUDIES, 2016

Université Sorbonne Nouvelle, Paris, France

CERTIFICATIONS

DATA AND BUSINESS ANALYTICS

- 1. Ask Questions to Make Data-Driven Decisions Google, 2021
- 2. Foundations: Data, Data, Everywhere Google, 2021
- 3. Introduction to Infographics and Data Visualization The University of Texas at Austin, 2014

FUTURES THINKING

- 1. Professional Certification Innovation and Futures Thinking Methodology Aerolito, 2021
- 2. Neoworkers: Professionals of the Future Aerolito, 2021
- 3. Collaborative Foresight Institute For The Future, 2020
- 4. Urgent Optimism: How to Turn Foresight into Action Institute For The Future, 2020
- 5. Forecasting Skills Institute For The Future, 2020
- 6. Introduction to Futures Thinking Institute For The Future, 2019
- 7. Simulation Skills Institute For The Future, 2019

CONTENT WRITING AND SEO

- 1. Corporate Blogging Specialist Rock Content, 2019
- 2. SEO (Search Engine Optimization) Rock Content, 2019
- 3. Content Production Specialist Rock Content, 2018
- 4. SEO: Academy For Beginners Mangools, 2017
- 5. SEO Training Course Moz, 2017

MARKETING

- 1. Inbound Marketing Rock Content, 2019
- 2. Content Marketing Certification HubSpot, 2017
- 3. Content Marketing Certification Rock Content, 2017
- 4. Inbound Certification HubSpot, 2016
- 5. Content Marketing Rock Content, 2016

COMMUNITY AND DIGITAL LITERACY

- 1. Twitter Community Management OpenClassrooms, 2015
- 2. HTML5 and CSS3 OpenClassrooms, 2015
- 3. Community Management OpenClassroms, 2015

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

KRYSTEL LEAL Page 3

Languages: English (Fluent), French (Native), Portuguese (Native)

Technical Proficiencies: Google Suite, Trello, Slack, Zapier, Project Planning, Search Engine Optimization (SEO), Content Management Systems (CMS), WordPress, Elementor, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, PHP

Interests: Reading, Writing, Blog Writing, Travel, Networking Events